Fiacre

Nsanzabandi

DATE OF BIRTH:

11/07/1988

CONTACT

Nationality: Burundian

Gender: Male

60 Rue de la gare, Residence
Capellen
8325 Capellen, Luxembourg



fayabobo@gmail.com



(+352)691988265



https://fiacre-nsanzabandi.com

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer experienced in Java EE programming. After 6 years of professional life in application development, I find it easy to integrate new projects and quickly acquire new knowledge on new subjects. I consider myself a dynamic, versatile and autodidact person and that allows me to be a very good team player. I like sharing the developer experience and it motivates me to move towards the professions of "tech leader", "team leader" or "scrum master".

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/05/2019 - CURRENT

Developer for different customers and internal projects

Sopra Steria

Clients

- UCM (Union des classes moyennes)
- BCP Luxembourg
- SIB (Steria interconection box)
- Sopra Steria digilab

Tasks

- o Conception & development of Java EE applications
- Participation in different POCs (Proof of concepts) aimed at improving the existing

Technical environment:

- WEB programming: Java EE, Spring batch, Spring boot, Angular, HTML5, CSS3
- Mobile programming: Android
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Google cloud platform, Ansible
- Collaboration & integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven, SVN
- Database: Oracle, Mysql

Methodology: Agile, scrum

Leudelange, Luxembourg

01/01/2018 - 30/04/2019

Developer for the customer " Oney Bank "

Sopra Steria

Tasks

- Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- o Technical leader in clean coding

Technical environment

- WEB programming: Java EE, Spring boot, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS
- Collaboration and integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven
- Database: Oracle, Mysql

Methodology: Agile

Customer's domain: Banking

La Madeleine, France

01/02/2016 - 31/12/2017

Developer for the customer « GIE AGORA » (IT center of the mutual health insurance for farmers in France)

Sopra Steria

Tasks

- Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Provide corrective maintenance
- Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers
- Analyst and team leader

Technical environment

- WEB Programming: Java EE, Struts, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3, C etc.
- o Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- Collaboration and integration: Jira, CVS
- Applications' performances: JMeter & JProfiler.

Methodology: Agile

Customer's domain: Insurance

La Madeleine, France

03/03/2014 - 31/01/2016

Developer for the client « AG2R LA MONDIALE »

Sopra Steria

Tasks

- o Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Provide corrective maintenance
- Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers

Technical environment

- WEBprogramming: Java EE, GWT, JSF, Spring, HTML5, CSS3
- Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- o Collaboration & integration: Jira, ARS, ITSM, HPQC, clearcase, CVS

Functional environment: Insurance

La Madeleine, France

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2011 - 01/08/2014 - Rouen, France

Master's degree in software engineering

Université de Rouen

Professional studies on:

- software development methodologies
- various programming languages (WEB programming, Java, Java EE, C++, C#, etc.)

01/09/2008 - 01/07/2011 - Oran, Algeria

Bachelor's degree in mathematics & computer science

Université d'Oran

Programming:

∘ Java, C++, Qt

• Functional programming: prolog, CAML. Mathematics: analyzes and algebra

Student scholarship of the Burundian government and UNESCO.

01/09/2007 - 01/06/2008

Gap year

Student at the University of Tanganyika Lake; Traveling across East Africa.

01/09/2006 - 01/07/2007 - Bujumbura, Burundi

Secondary studies achievement in mathematics and physics
Lycée du Lac Tanganyika

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Job-related skills

- **Programming languages**: Java, Kotlin, typescript, C++, C, C#, SQL, etc.
- **WEB programming**: Java EE (JSP/Servlet, etc.), Spring (Spring boot, Spring MVC, etc.), Angular, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, etc.
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Ansible, Google cloud platform
- JavaEE tools/frameworks: Playframework, GWT, Zkoss, JUnit, AspectJ, SoapUI, postman etc.
- Profiling and performances: JMeter et JProfiler
- Mobile development: développeur android junior
- Collaboration et integration: Git, CVS, Maven, Nexus, Sonar, Jenkins, Jira
- Project management: Agile methods (Scrum, XP)
- Development tools (IDE): Eclipse, Intellij
- Database tools: MySQL, Postgresql, Oracle, non-relational databases notions (eXist)
- Servers: Tomcat, TomEE, glassfish, JBoss, Weblogic
- o OS: Linux & Windows

I am a full stack developer: 60% of my time doing java EE and 40% working on other technologies.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): French | Kirundi | Swahili

English

Listening C2	Reading C2	Spoken production C2	Spoken interaction C2	Writing C1
German				
Listening B1	Reading B1	Spoken production B2	Spoken interaction B2	Writing B1

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: AM / Driving Licence: B1 / Driving Licence: B